aolbroadband.co.uk 2007-12-12

# Privacy Policy

**Your AOL services are provided on the following basis:**

  * AOL Access Services (including internet access and AOL Talk) by TPH Services Sàrl 
  * AOL Web Services, including the AOL Software and Premium Services, are provided by AOL (UK) Limited. 

To find out how both companies use your personal information, please read TPH Services Sàrl Privacy Policy which applies to the AOL Access Services; and AOL (UK) Ltd Privacy Policy which applies to your use of the AOL Web Services.

**TPH Services Sàrl Privacy Policy**

The AOL Access service is provided by TPH Services Sàrl (“ **TPH** ”, “ **We** ”, “ **Us** ”). We regard our customers' privacy as one of our most important values. We want you to know how we protect customer data and what choices you have about its use. We believe our Privacy Policy should give you confidence whenever you use our services - 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days of the year. 

We have organised our policy into three parts: 

(1) We outline our Seven Principles of Privacy, our core commitment to protect your privacy. 

(2) We explain how we implement each principle. 

(3) We provide Helpful Tips on how you can better protect your privacy in cyberspace.

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT: THE SEVEN PRINCIPLES OF PRIVACY**

We are committed to protecting your personal privacy. Our Seven Principles of Privacy summarise and clarify that commitment: how we safeguard your privacy, how we treat personal information, and what choices you have. We understand that for you to take full advantage of the benefits of this interactive medium, we must do everything we can to ensure that your privacy is secure.

  1. We do not read your private online communications. 
  2. We can identify you as an individual when you use the AOL Access Services and we may personalise your experience based such use. We do not give this information out to others. 
  3. We do not give out your telephone number, Billing Account information or screen names, unless you authorise us to do so. And we give you the opportunity to correct your personal contact and Billing Account information at any time. 
  4. We may use information about the kinds of products you buy from us to make other marketing offers to you, unless you tell us not to. We do not give out this purchase data to others. 
  5. We give you choices about how we use your personal information. 
  6. We use secure technology, privacy protection controls and restrictions on employee access in order to safeguard your personal information. 
  7. We will keep you informed, clearly and prominently, about what we do with your personal information, and we will advise you if we change our policy. 

**_

PRINCIPLE 1

_**

**We do not read your private online communications**.

We honour the confidentiality of our customers' private communications in e-mail (including downloads) and via AOL Talk. We do not read or disclose private communications without your consent to third parties except where we or an entity processing your data on our behalf is compelled to do so by law, or in response to a valid, legally compliant request by a competent authority, to protect the company's rights and property, or during emergencies when we believe physical safety is at risk.

**_

PRINCIPLE 2 

_**

Our systems automatically gather information about your use of the AOL Access Services and we may use this together with other aggregated information to improve our services and personalise your experience of the AOL Access Services. We also use navigational information in the aggregate to understand how our customers as a group use the service so that we can make our service better. We may also share this statistical information with our partners or other outside companies, but in doing so, we don't disclose individual names or personal navigational information. 

**We do not keep track of where you personally go on the World Wide Web**.

We may use cookies and other analogous technologies to improve your online experience. You may control your preferences, and find out more detailed information in relation to these technologies at <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/cookies>. We may use these technologies to personalise and enhance your experience on our service, including to:

  1. Maintain data that you voluntarily give us about your preferences, such as your personal interests; 
  2. Validate participation in select online activities, such as making sure that each person only votes in an online poll once; and 
  3. Authenticate your access to your personal data for added security. 

The Web sites you visit should have their own privacy policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of Web sites before providing them with any of your personal data.

**_

PRINCIPLE 3

_**

 **We do not give out your telephone number, Billing Account information or screen names, unless you authorise us to do so. And we give you the opportunity to correct your personal contact and billing information at any time.**

When you join the AOL Access Service, we ask you for your name, address, telephone number, and Billing Account information - including the credit card, bank account, or debit card used to pay for your account. Here is how we protect that information:

  * We will not give out your telephone number or screen names (e-mail addresses), except where needed to deliver a product or service you ordered. 
  * We will not give out your Billing Account information unless you authorise it, for example, during an online purchase. 

We make lists of customers' contact information available to other companies within the Carphone Warehouse Group of companies and to pre-screened third-party companies who have product or service offers we think may be of interest to you. We also sometimes combine these lists with publicly available information or segment them based on other information, such as when a customer joined us or a customer's computer system type. These lists are never based on a customer's online activities.

You may choose to remove your name and address from the mailing lists we provide to other companies. For more information about your choices, please see Principle 5.

We also collect and use other information for internal purposes. For example, we keep records in your account history of your complaints about other customers' online behaviour, your contact with our Customer Services department and any reported violations of our terms and conditions) that you or someone on your account may have committed. Our systems and software automatically query your computer for information about your computer system such as the speed of your modem, error messages you may have received, or whether you use a particular type of software or hardware to access the internet - to help us fit the service to your individual needs and to help us diagnose problems you may be having with your system.

We have two exceptions to these policies: We will release specific information about your account only to comply with valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order, or in special cases such as a physical threat to you or others.

We provide you with the opportunity to update or correct your contact and billing information that we have on file. Just as you want to make sure that information we have about you is accurate, we want to keep only the most up-to-date information about your account. Therefore, whenever you believe that your contact or billing information needs updating, you can go to <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/billing> and make the necessary changes. 

**_

PRINCIPLE 4

_**

 **We may use information about the kinds of products or services you buy from us to make other marketing offers to you, unless you tell us not to. We do not give out this purchase data to others.**

_Your Purchases From Us  
_We may offer users the opportunity to buy merchandise directly from us, such as computer hardware and software, and other products or services. Like other retailers and direct marketers, we record information about such purchases. When you buy from us online, our system automatically gathers purchase data, and we also record information about purchases made through our telemarketing, mail order and other marketing operations.

We may use this information in the following ways: 

  1. We review what kinds of products and services appeal most to our customers as a group. This statistical information helps us improve our offerings in the same way that other companies change their catalogue based on what sells best. 
  2. We use information such as the number of purchases customers make and the categories of goods and services they buy to make offers to you that we believe will interest you. In addition, we use other information such as when customers joined us, how often they use the service or their type of computer system to make such offers. We also use publicly available consumer data to help us decide which marketing offers to make and which advertising they see. 

You may choose not to receive marketing offers from us. For more information about your choices, please see Principle 5. 

We do not give out any information about what you, as an individual, purchase from us, except to complete your transactions, or otherwise as set out in this privacy policy. We share with outside companies only statistical information about what AOL Access products or services our customers - as a group - buy.

_Your Other Online Purchases Through Our Service_   
For all other online purchases, be sure to review the merchants' privacy policies and contact them directly if you have any questions. They may have privacy terms that differ from our privacy policy, and they may use personal information which you may provide them differently than our policy permits. 

We may be involved in facilitating your purchases from these other companies, but this individual data is not used for any other purpose.

**_

PRINCIPLE 5 

_**

**We give you choices about how we use your personal information**. 

You have choices about how the information you have provided may be used by us to make special offers to you. And you can direct us to remove your contact details such as your name and address from mailing lists we provide to selected, pre-screened companies. 

To activate any of these marketing preferences, go to <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/marketingprefs>. 

  * You may choose not to receive marketing offers from third parties about their products and services by post 
  * You may choose not to receive marketing offers from us by post. 
  * You may choose not to receive marketing offers from us by telephone. 
  * You may choose not to receive marketing offers from us by e-mail. 
  * You may choose not to receive marketing offers from us through online "pop-up screens." 

**_

PRINCIPLE 6

_**

**We use secure technology, privacy protection controls and restrictions on employee access in order to safeguard your personal information**.

We use state-of-the-art technology to keep your personal information - including your billing and account information - as secure as possible. We also have put in place privacy protection control systems designed to ensure that your personal data remain safe and private 

Each and every one of our employees must abide by our privacy policy. Only authorised employees and suppliers are permitted to have access to your personal information and such access is limited by need. For example, if you call our Customer Services department with a concern or complaint, the representative is allowed to access only the personal information that he or she needs to address your concern. In addition, any company with which we contracts to be our agent in conducting our business is required to adhere to confidentiality agreements to ensure that your information remains safe and secure. 

All our employees are required to acknowledge that they understand and will comply with this privacy policy. Employees who violate our privacy policies are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including dismissal. 

We strongly encourage our content, commerce and advertising partners to post clearly their own privacy policies and to have privacy control systems in place to protect your personal information. Be sure to review their privacy policies and contact them directly if you have any questions.

**_

PRINCIPLE 7

_**

**We will keep you informed, clearly and prominently, about what we do with your personal information, and we will advise you if we change our policy**.

A key part of our commitment to protecting your privacy is explaining to you how we may use your personal information. This privacy policy serves that purpose, and it is accessible through several means within our service. When you register for our service, you are presented with the main terms of our privacy policy and should familiarise yourself with this and all our other policies at that time. In addition, this policy is easily located in our Conditions of Service area at <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/cos>.

Whenever we change our policy, we will give you 30 days' notice of those changes through prominent disclosures, including notification on our front screen. If policy changes are substantial, we will notify each of our customers individually through pop-up screens or e-mails. Since pop-ups last only for a limited time, however, you should sign on to your account regularly for these and other important announcements. 

Business transfers **.** The online world and our business continue to evolve, and we may purchase or sell business units, take over other companies, (or we may ourselves be taken over) or carry out corporate reorganisations. In such transactions, customer information may form one of the transferred business assets. Any entity receiving such personal data will remain bound to the Privacy Policy set out here and in the Access Services Agreements. 

The TPH Services Sàrl Privacy Policy set out above should be should be read subject to the following: We may disclose data about your account if we or an entity processing your data on our behalf is compelled to do so by law or in response to a valid, legally compliant request by a competent authority, or with your consent. 

If you'd like to comment on or have questions about our privacy policy, or if you have a concern or policy violation you wish to report, you can email us at [datainfo@aolbroadband.co.uk](mailto:datainfo@aolbroadband.co.uk), or write to us c/o Data Protection, Customer Services, CPW Broadband Services (Ireland) Ltd, IDA Business Park, Cork Road, Waterford, Ireland or Data Protection, TPH Services Sàrl, a company registered in Luxembourg under name B 122 040 with a corporate address at Green Office Park, Parc d' Activités Syrdall 6, L-5365 Munsbach, Grand Duchy of Luxembourg. or via email at [datainfo@aolbroadband.co.uk](mailto:datainfo@aolbroadband.co.uk).

** SOME TIPS TO HELP YOU PROTECT YOUR PRIVACY AND SECURITY ONLINE **

You can take the responsibility to protect your personal privacy online. Here is a checklist that will help safeguard your privacy and protect the integrity of your computer and AOL Access account. We urge you to print these tips and post them near your computer for you and your children.

  1. Never give your password to anyone online. Never give your billing information except to facilitate a purchase. 
  2. Make your password at least 6 characters in length. Create a password that includes a combination of numbers and letters (such as sun8ray or bel3jar2 or 12hat93). Be sure to use different passwords for each screen name on your account. 
  3. If you have fallen for an online scam and given out your password, change your password right away. Before you sign off, go to <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/password> and create a new password for your screen name. Also, change the passwords for any other screen names on your account. 
  4. Your computer can catch a virus by simply opening an e-mail, so exercise caution if opening an email from someone you don’t know and consider installing virus detecting software. If an e-mail asks for a password or billing information, or contains a suspicious file attachment from someone you don't know, go to <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/notify> to learn how to report it. 
  5. Never download files unless you know what they are and who sent them to you. Computer viruses and destructive programs that could cause your computer to divulge personal information are often transferred in cleverly disguised files. 
  6. When you go on the Web, you may want to check the sites you visit to see if they have a privacy policy. Take special care to protect your personal information and your screen name, since the operators of Web sites are not bound by the TPH Services Sàrl Privacy Policy. 
  7. Explain to your children that some contests or prize draws provided by other parties could ask them for personal information, and make very clear what information they may or may not provide, under any circumstances. 
  8. You can get instructions to report any violation by going to <http://myaolbroadband.co.uk/notify>. 

**The AOL Access Service is provided by TPH Services Sàrl, a company registered in Luxembourg under name B 122 040 with a corporate address at Green Office Park, Parc d' Activités Syrdall 6, L-5365 Munsbach, Grand Duchy of Luxembourg. Please use the dedicated contact details specified above to ensure prompt processing of your requests.**

**AOL (UK) Limited Privacy Policy**

**AOL’s Commitment to protecting your privacy**

A key part of AOL's commitment to protecting your privacy is to explain how we may use the personal information we collect, the choices you have about its use, and the steps we take to help protect your privacy whilst you interact with AOL. 

In the provision of the web based [sites, pages, AOL Web Services and software](http://help.aol.co.uk/article/20070131100709990010) (collectively the " **AOL Web Services** ") AOL (UK) Limited, our subsidiaries and/or affiliated companies (together the " **AOL Group Companies** ") **(“AOL” or “we” or “our”)** and other data processors acting under our control may collect, process, store and use aggregate information, and any information which may identify you or your Web Services Account (your “ **Personal Information** ”) in various different ways and for different purposes.  AOL collects this information when you give this to us or when you interact with the AOL Web Services.

Access to some of the AOL Web Services may require you to complete a registration process and to open an account with AOL (the “ **Web Services** **Account** ”). When you go through this Web Services Account registration process, you are presented with the main terms of our Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is also easily found online by clicking on the Privacy Policy links on AOL’s Web Sites, or at www.aol.co.uk/privacy. 

AOL controls the Personal Information you provide to us when you register and when you use the AOL Web Services.  We will process your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, the [AOL Web Services Agreement](http://help.aol.co.uk/article/20070125072109990001) **** and applicable law, and we take responsibility for the processing, disclosure, and use of that information, including use by a third party on our behalf.  When you register and by using the AOL Web Services you agree to this use.

**AOL's Privacy Commitment: The Seven Principles of Privacy**

Here we outline our Seven Principles of Privacy, which summarise and clarify AOL’s commitments to protect your privacy. ****

  1. **We are straightforward about what Personal Information we collect, and how we use it.   We tell you how you can contact us with any questions or suggestions you may have**.  
We tell you what Personal Information we collect and how we use it; where it will be stored and long it will be kept and we tell you how we will notify you if this Privacy Policy changes and how to contact us to. Read more
  2. **We may personalise your experience based on how you use the AOL Web Services, including where you go on the AOL Web Services.**  
When you use the AOL Web Services you are not anonymous – for example when you log in using your Screen Name - we can identify you as an individual when you visit AOL and we may personalise your experience based on the information you submit and how you use the AOL Web Services.   Read more
  3. **We give you choices about how AOL uses your Personal Information.**  
You can edit your Personal Information, set your marketing preferences, or find out more about how to set or change other product controls and preferences which make the AOL Web Services more relevant and convenient for you.  Read more
  4. **We do not give out any Personal Financial Information you may provide us with, unless you authorise us to do so.   And we give you the opportunity to correct your personal details at any time.   
**When you use AOL Web Services, which incur a charge, we may ask you for your name, address, telephone number, and payment details in order to take a payment from you. However, we will not give out such information unless you authorise it. Read more
  5. **We do not read your private online communications.  
**We respect the confidentiality of your private communications, like e-mail and Instant Messages. We do not read or disclose these communications except in limited circumstances (such as in response to a court order). Read more
  6. **We use technology, privacy protection controls and restrictions on employee access in order to help safeguard your Personal Information.**   
We use technology to help keep your Personal Information as secure as it reasonably can be. Read more  

  7. **We take extra steps to help protect the safety and privacy of children.**   
Young people need special safeguards and privacy protection. We have special privacy practices to help protect kids and teens when they use the AOL Web Services specifically designed for them. Read more  

**AOL’s Privacy Policy is subject to the following important provisions** : 

We (or data processors acting under our control) will only disclose your information to third parties if you have consented (or not objected) to us doing so.  However, we may be obliged to disclose information about your Web Services Account in the following circumstances:

  * if we or an entity processing your information on our behalf is compelled to do so by law;
  * in response to a valid, legally compliant request by a competent authority; 
  * in special cases such as a physical threat to you or others; and/or 
  * otherwise in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

**_PRINCIPLE 1_**

**We are straightforward about what Personal Information we collect, and how we use it.   We tell you how you can contact us with any questions or suggestions you may have**. ****

**What Personal Information does AOL collect?** Depending on how you use the AOL Web Services, Personal Information collected may include: ****

  * information (which may include for example your name, delivery address, email, date of birth, gender, occupation, industry, and personal interests, postcode and billing information) provided when you:  
 •  register for a Web Services Account or interact with the AOL Web Services (e.g. so we can offer you localised AOL Web Services);   
 •  order products or AOL Web Services from AOL or our online merchants or advertisers;  
 •  enter competitions or promotions; or  
 •  take part in market research; 
  * your customer service information (including Web Services Account activity histories and records of your communications with our customer services team);
  * records of your communications with us (whether in writing, by email or by telephone) for the training and monitoring of our staff and to improve our service; 
  * information about your online activities - **** for example, your patterns of browsing, clicking, purchasing and searches you perform when using the AOL Web Services **** \- so that we can tailor your experience of the AOL Web Services **** according to your apparent preferences, as expressed through those patterns of activity; Read More
  * technical and diagnostic information gathered or received when you use the AOL Web Services. Some of the technical information that may be collected or received includes: the type of browser you are using (e.g., Netscape, AOL Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), CPU type (e.g. Pentium), the manner in which you connect to the Internet (e.g., your Internet Service provider and your connection speed through dial-up or broadband access); Internet protocol address; other information about your geographic location; or data relating to computer malfunctions or problems occurring when you use your computer to access the AOL Web Services. Additionally, we may collect information about other software on your computer for protecting your security or improving your online experience. 

AOL may use so called “cookie” technology to gather information about your visits to and use of the AOL Web Services.  This information may include your responses to content, advertisements and product offerings provided to you.  For more detailed information Read More

The Personal Information we collect may be supplemented with information (including commercially available demographic information), which we obtain from other companies which we may use to better understand you as a customer and to provide all our users with better, more relevant content, advertisements and better designed communications, products and AOL Web Services. **

How does AOL use my Personal Information?

** AOL (or third parties acting under AOL’s control) may use your Personal Information to:

  * operate, analyse and improve the AOL Web Services and to enhance your online experience – for example, by authenticating your access to the AOL Web Services and to your Personal Information; 
  * communicate with you by mail, post, phone, electronic mail (including email, text, picture, video and SMS messaging), about offers and information on the products and AOL Web Services offered by AOL or third parties. Read More
  * personalise the content, advertising and promotions you receive and our communications with you, (e.g. finding out which advertisements you react to or the areas of the AOL Web Services which you visit most frequently or searches you perform on when using the AOL Web Services and tailoring your experience accordingly). Read More
  * contact you to provide tailored advice if we consider that you are experiencing technical issues that we reasonably consider may be adversely affecting your ability to use the AOL Web Services or to identify or fix possible threats to your safety, security, privacy, or to your computer's security;
  * conduct research and analysis.  This may involve contacting you to ask you for your feedback on your experiences whilst using the AOL Web Services;
  * contact you (or, in certain circumstances pass your contact details to pre-selected third parties) for marketing purposes.  For more information. Read More
  * transfer information about you if AOL purchase or sell business units, take over other companies, (or is taken over) or carry out corporate reorganisations. Your Personal Information may be disclosed or transferred along with other business assets, to actual or potential purchasers. However the Privacy Policy will remain binding and your Personal Information will be subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations. 
  * If we collect any sensitive Personal Information, (for example about your health or lifestyle) we will not use this information without your explicit consent. 

If we propose to use your Personal Information in a way which is not covered by this Privacy Policy, we’ll tell you how we propose to use it at the time we collect it.  **

What happens if this Privacy Policy changes?

**

Whenever we materially change the Privacy Policy, we will give 30 days' notice of those changes through prominent disclosures, which may include online notification at AOL Keyword: Privacy and on the AOL Web Services.  We recommend you sign on to your Web Services Account regularly and check our sites online for these and other important announcements.           

**Where will my Personal Information be stored?**

AOL is a global organisation, and many of the computers and companies that process information on our behalf are based in the USA and other countries outside the European Economic Area (the " **EEA** "). This means that your Personal Information (which may include information you provide about your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, or concerning health or sex life) may be transferred to, processed and held both inside and outside the EEA.

These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the EEA.  However, if we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected in compliance with applicable data protection law and this Privacy Policy.  Details of companies and countries processing your information will be provided on request, by writing to AOL (UK) Limited, Legal Department 68 Hammersmith Road, London, W14 8YW. 

**How long will you keep my Personal Information?**

We may retain your Personal Information as long as is necessary for the purposes for which we collected it, or for the period to which you consent under the AOL Web Services Agreement, as explained here or under the specific terms applicable to your use of the AOL Web Services, or as is otherwise required by applicable law.  We may process your Personal Information for a reasonable period after your use of the AOL Web Services ceases. 

If you have purchased any paid for AOL Web Services from AOL we may retain payment-related information, such as a payment card number which you supplied to us (but only in an anonymised form which does not enable us to identify the holder of that payment method) for an unlimited period after your paid for AOL Web Services or Web Services Account has been cancelled for fraud prevention purposes.  Read More

We will look after the security of the information you provide: Read More

**How can I find out more about how my Personal Information is used?**

The online world evolves, and so will the way AOL uses your Personal Information.  If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, or if you have a concern or policy violation you wish to tell us about, or wish to see the Personal Data we keep about you (as defined in the Data Protection Act 1988) you may contact us by email at [datainfouk@aol.com](mailto:datainfouk@aol.com), or write to us at: AOL (UK) Limited, Legal Department, 68 Hammersmith Road, London, W14 8YW. 

If your enquiry is a customer service enquiry, which is not related to AOL’s use of your Personal Information, please contact us by visiting: [Contact AOL](http://help.aol.co.uk/article/20070131115209990001)

**_PRINCIPLE 2_**

We may personalise your experience based on how you use the AOL Web Services, including where you go on the AOL Web Services. 

Our systems may automatically gather information about your usage of the AOL Web Services.  We may use both Personal Information and other aggregated information to improve AOL’s service and personalise your experience of the AOL Web Services, including in the following ways:    

  * To tailor the content, communications, advertisements or promotions you receive when using the AOL Web Services. 

For example, we might use information about your visits to the AOL Film Downloads Channel to personalise the advertisements you see. We may do this based on the details you have submitted, your expressed preferences and your online activity, how often you use the service, or the type of computer system you use, together with the activities and experiences of other AOL users who we believe may have similar interests and preferences to you. We may supplement this data with publicly available consumer data, including demographic information, **** to help us decide how to make your experience more relevant; and  We may also provide you with content and advertisements around the AOL Web Services which may be customised using information such as the search terms you use on the AOL Web Services – for example, if you search for “football” you might see more content and advertisements relating to “sports” and related subject matter areas. 

  * We may use navigational information about where you go on the AOL Web Services to better understand how AOL Web Services are used, and what content and advertisements our users enjoy so that we can make AOL better. 
  * We do not use any navigational data about where you, as an individual, go, or what products or services you use on the wider internet outside the AOL Web Services, save where such sites provide for such use in their respective privacy policies. 
  * We may collect Personal Information and aggregated data, relating to how often and frequently visitors use elements of the AOL Web Services so that we can measure the popularity and usage of those and use this information to improve the AOL Web Services.

**Cookies, Web beacons and your options**

AOL may use cookies, web beacons or similar technologies to enhance and personalise your online experience and to enable AOL to recognise you as a previous visitor to the AOL Web Services. AOL may also allow its partners and advertisers that are presenting advertisements on the AOL Web Services to set their cookies, or apply web beacons or similar technologies, to your computer. This information may be used to: 

  * remember the preferences and registration data that you give us; 
  * authenticate your Screen Name before you can access your Personal Information or Web Services Account for added security 
  * enable you to participate in certain online activities, such as making sure that each person only votes in an online poll once; 
  * personalise features of the AOL Web Services, for example by providing you with customised content (e.g. a localised weather forecast) or advertisements based on the information you have submitted to us and your activity when using the AOL Web Services; 
  * help measure and research the effectiveness of the AOL Web Services, including collecting statistics on your response to advertisements, e-mail and other communications you receive; 
  * provide security within shopping baskets or transactions. 

AOL and its advertisers may also use ad network providers, including AOL subsidiaries such as Advertising.com, to help present advertisements on AOL Web Services and other Web sites. These ad network providers may use [cookies, or web beacons or similar technologies](http://www.aol.co.uk/what-are-cookies) _ ****_ on your computer to tailor content, advertisements to your preferences, help target, measure and track your visits and the effectiveness of advertisements and promotions, using data gathered over time and across their networks of Web pages to determine or predict the characteristics and preferences of their audience and to provide security within shopping baskets or transactions. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by Advertising.com and other ad network providers is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. To find out more about ad network providers and the choices you have about these technologies [click here](http://help.aol.co.uk/article/20060802095209990025)

You can adjust the settings on your browser to erase or block such technologies from your computer if you want to, but if you do so, you may not be able to use or access certain features of the AOL Web Services or other companies web sites may not work very well.  For more detailed information on these technologies and how to disable them visit: AOL Keyword: [Cookies](aol://1722:cookies) or if you do not use AOL software, to find out more visit [www.aol.co.uk](http://www.aol.co.uk/what-are-cookies).

**_PRINCIPLE 3_**

**We give you choices about how AOL uses your Personal Information.**

AOL may use your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our AOL Web Services Agreement. You can tell us about your preferences regarding how your Personal Information is used for marketing purposes, and review and change your marketing preferences at any time, by visiting: Keyword [Marketing Preferences](aol://1722:MarketingPreferences) or if you are a portal user, <http://www.aol.co.uk/marketingprefs>.

**Will I receive marketing communications from AOL?** Unless you tell us otherwise we may contact you by post (or telephone) to let you know about products and AOL Web Services that we think may be of interest to you.   We’ll only do this by email, SMS and other similar forms of communication where we’re letting you know about AOL’s goods and AOL Web Services similar to AOL Web Services you have used, or if you’ve told us that you’d like this to happen.

**Will AOL pass my Personal Information to other companies for them to send marketing communications to me?** Unless you tell us otherwise we may pass on your postal and telephone contact details to selected companies who may contact you by post (or telephone) to let you know about products and AOL Web Services that they think may be of interest to you.   We’ll only pass on your email, SMS and other similar forms of address where you’ve clearly indicated that you’d like this to happen.  AOL will not rent or sell your Personal Information to third parties.

However, for all online purchases that you may make from third parties whilst online with AOL, make sure that you review their privacy policies and contact them directly if you have any questions.  They may have privacy policies that differ from AOL's, and they may therefore use Personal Information which you provide to them differently.

You can review and change your marketing preferences at any time by visiting: Keyword [Marketing Preferences](aol://1722:MarketingPreferences), or, if you do not use AOL Software at <http://www.aol.co.uk/marketingprefs>.

Some AOL Web Services allow you to control what information is collected or used when you use that offering.

**Can I customise my experience of AOL using AOL software?** AOL’s client software offers you lots of flexibility in how the AOL Web Services are made available to you. You can easily amend your AOL settings, to make your experience more relevant to you (for example, you can create personalised email stationery and web page).  If you are enjoying AOL Web Services as a web user, then you may also tailor your experience – we provide links in appropriate areas, or visit <http://www.aol.co.uk/help>.

As the choices you make about your preferences and settings may not take effect immediately, it is possible you may receive a communication which you have requested not to receive during the period in which your request is being processed.

**What happens when my Web Services Account is cancelled?**

If you cancel your Web Services Account or AOL cancels your Web Services Account (see the AOL Web Services Agreement), unless and until you indicate otherwise, your name, address, email address (other than your AOL web mail email address) and telephone number may: 

  1. be used by AOL Group Companies during and for a reasonable period of time after your Web Services Account is cancelled for the purposes described above; and 
  2. passed to selected third party suppliers of goods and AOL Web Services and advertisers until 6 months after your Web Services Account is cancelled, for marketing goods and AOL Web Services to you by post or by telephone. 

If you have any other questions, please get in touch and we’ll do our best to help. For details on how to contact us visit [Contact AOL](http://info.aol.co.uk/about/contact/).

**_PRINCIPLE 4_** ** __**

**We do not give out your payment details, unless you authorise us to do so.   And we give you the opportunity to correct your personal details at any time.  **

If you request a product or service which requires payment, we may collect payment details and ask you for your name, address, telephone number and an alternative email address.

We will not give out such information unless you authorise it, for example, during an online purchase. However, if you provide us with a payment method which belongs to someone else, we may disclose your name and address, and data relating to payments made by that method to them.

  Just as you want to make sure that information AOL has about you is accurate, we want to keep only the most up-to-date information about your Web Services Account.  We provide you with the opportunity to update or correct your contact and billing information that we have on file **.   **AOL Keyword: [Billing](aol://1722:billing) or [click here](http://help.aol.co.uk/account-questions/article/20060627121509990005).

**If you provide someone else’s payment details to pay for any AOL Web Services.**

You _MUST_ obtain that party’s express consent before you do this.  If you do provide a third party’s payment details to pay for a Service - for example, you provide the payment details of a partner or a friend to pay - we may disclose your name and address and information to them relating to payments made in relation to your Web Services Account.

For marketing purposes, we may provide your Personal Information (including contact details) to other companies whose products and AOL Web Services may be of interest to you. For more information about your choices, please see Principle 3.

**_PRINCIPLE 5_** __

**We do not read your private online communications.**

AOL honours the confidentiality of your private online communications in private chat rooms, email (including downloads), and Instant Message conversations.  AOL does not read, or disclose to third parties, private communications when you use the AOL Web Services, without your consent, except where we or an affiliate processing your data on our behalf is compelled to do so by law, or in response to a valid, legally compliant request by a competent authority, or during emergencies when we believe physical safety is at risk. 

Of course, what you write or post in public or member chat rooms and message boards is available to the public.

**_PRINCIPLE 6_**

**We use secure technology, privacy protection controls and restrictions on employee access in order to safeguard your Personal Information.**

We use technology and other means to help keep your Personal Information, including your Web Services Account information and any payment details you may provide to us, as safe it reasonably can be. We also have put in place privacy protection control systems designed to help ensure that your Personal Information remains safe and private.

To help protect the information you provide to we may use a variety of safeguards, including: 

  * technical, administrative, and physical controls (such as restricted access facilities, intrusion prevention and detection systems, and dedicated security personnel and incident response teams) 
  * encryption and authentication systems 
  * passwords, and other methods including Account Security Questions and 
  * agreements with contractors and vendors requiring them to protect the confidentiality, safety, and security of your information 

Each and every AOL employee must comply with the AOL Privacy Policy. AOL authorises its employees to obtain access your Personal Information only to perform their particular functions, and uses technological and other control procedures to help limit such access. Employees who violate our policies and practices are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including dismissal, or prosecution where appropriate. 

AOL Group Companies may use other third parties in order to help operate the AOL Web Services. We require such third parties that have access to your Personal Information to protect this information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy and otherwise in accordance with applicable law. 

AOL has established these safeguards to help prevent unauthorised access to or misuse of your Personal Information, but cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Policy (for example, as a result of unauthorised acts by third parties that violate applicable law or AOL’s policies). 

There are many ways for you to access the AOL Web Services, including through high speed and wireless connections – please see your own provider for details. 

We offer you a robust set of tools to help you prevent others from gaining access to your Personal Information, as well as to help protect against other threats to the security of your online experience. To learn what you can do to help safeguard your safety, security, and privacy, please visit <http://help.aol.co.uk/help-safety>.

**_PRINCIPLE 7_**

**We take extra steps to protect the safety and privacy of children.**

Young people need special safeguards and privacy protection. We realise they may not understand all the provisions of our policy or be able to make thoughtful decisions about the choices available to adult members. So we have special privacy practices to protect kids using areas on the service specifically designed for them. We urge all parents to educate their children about online safety and the need to protect their Personal Information. 

In areas of the AOL Web Services which may be designed for children 14 and under, AOL and its partners require parental consent (for example, by sending in a permission form by regular mail or by fax) to collect or use names, addresses, telephone numbers or other information that identifies a child offline. ****

In areas of the AOL Web Services which may be designed for teens aged 13 to 17, AOL and its partners may not collect names, addresses, telephone numbers or other Personal Information of anyone under the age of 14 without disclosing how that information will be used. 

If you have further queries in relation to your personal data, you may email [datainfouk@aol.com](mailto:datainfouk@aol.com). 

Last Updated: October 2007
